<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>!! Mod Config Menu - Pure</name>
    <directory>!!mod config menu</directory>
    <id>2681875787</id>
    <description>[h1][b]Mod Config Menu - Pure Version[/b][/h1]

Mod Config Menu is a library to that allows other mods to have a settings menu. You should only subscribe to this mod if you have other mods that use it.

Help with the development of this mod by [contributing on GitHub](https://github.com/Zamiell/isaac-mod-config-menu).

Credit goes to piber20 for originally creating this library and Chifilly for updating it for Repentance.

This version of Mod Config Menu removes all of the hacky API overrides that piber put into the original, which is a terrible programming practice and causes problems with other things in the Isaac ecosystem.

In order to use this mod, do not `require` or `pcall` anything. Rather, simply check to see if the global variable exists:

[code]
local function setupMyModConfigMenuSettings()
  if ModConfigMenu == nil then
    return
  end

  ModConfigMenu.AddSpace(&quot;My Mod&quot;, &quot;Info&quot;)
  ModConfigMenu.AddText(&quot;My Mod&quot;, &quot;Info&quot;, function() return &quot;My Mod&quot; end)
  ModConfigMenu.AddSpace(&quot;My Mod&quot;, &quot;Info&quot;)
  ModConfigMenu.AddText(&quot;My Mod&quot;, &quot;Info&quot;, function() return &quot;Version 1.0&quot; end)
end
[/code]

Note that the &quot;Pure&quot; version of Mod Config Menu will not work properly if:
- you subscribed to the &quot;Pure&quot; version and you subscribed to a different version at the same time, causing a conflict
- you are subscribed to a mod that uses a standalone version of Mod Config Menu, causing a conflict
- a mod uses the `require` or `pcall` functions to initialize or invoke Mod Config Menu



[h1]Navigation[/h1]

Keyboard:
Use the arrow keys or WASD keys to move around

Esc, backspace, or Q can be used to go back

E, space, or enter can be used to select an item.

By default you can open the menu by pressing L.

F10 will also always open the menu, this cannot be changed.

Controller:
Both control sticks can be used to move around, press B to go back, A to select an item.

By default you can open the menu by pressing down the right control stick.

</description>
    <version>1.2</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
</metadata>
