<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>!!(REP) Mod Config Menu</name>
    <directory>!!mod config menu</directory>
    <id>2487535818</id>
    <description>QUICK PORT TO REPENTANCE

This is a quick update to fix the main issue of the mods list being empty when opening the mod menu. I have not checked for or fix any other issues that may exist.

My fork is available here: https://gitlab.com/Chifilly/bindingofisaac-modconfigmenu if anyone wants to fork it themselves or issue pull requests.

I am NOT well versed in BoI modding, so anyone else feel free to take the reins if you feel you can do a better job.

Original description below

----------

This mod is free for anyone else to reupload and modify as I take a possibly permanent hiatus.
https://gitlab.com/piber20/bindingofisaac-modconfigmenu






The Mod Config Menu is a mod that adds a new menu to the game that enables other mods to provide a simple and easy way for the player to configure them.

This mod does not do much on its own, to get into the real action you should download a mod which supports this menu.


[h1]My mods dont work![/h1]
- Make sure you have the latest version of mod config menu, visible in the mod config menu category
- Restart the game!

If you still have issues even after doing all this, please report them to me, and provide any error logs if you have any.


[h1]Navigation[/h1]

Keyboard:
Use the arrow keys or WASD keys to move around

Esc, backspace, or Q can be used to go back

E, space, or enter can be used to select an item.

By default you can open the menu by pressing L.

F10 will also always open the menu, this cannot be changed.

Controller:
Both control sticks can be used to move around, press B to go back, A to select an item.

By default you can open the menu by pressing down the right control stick.



Join my discord server!
https://discord.com/invite/uJEFFdb

Support me on patreon!
https://www.patreon.com/piber20</description>
    <version>1.39</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
</metadata>
